<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Verse Today</string>
    <string-array name="All_Verses">
         <item>When you are blue , Psalms 42:5 Why are you [a]cast down, O my soul?
And why are you disquieted within me?
Hope in God, for I shall yet praise Him
[b]For the help of His countenance.</item>
        <item>
             When tempted to do wrong, Matthew 4:1-11Then Jesus was led up by the Spirit into the wilderness to be tempted by the devil. 2 And when He had fasted forty days and forty nights, afterward He was hungry. 3 Now when the tempter came to Him, he said, “If You are the Son of God, command that these stones become bread.”

4 But He answered and said, “It is written, ‘Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceeds from the mouth of God.’ ”

5 Then the devil took Him up into the holy city, set Him on the pinnacle of the temple, 6 and said to Him, “If You are the Son of God, throw Yourself down. For it is written:

‘He shall give His angels charge over you,’

and,

‘In their hands they shall bear you up,
Lest you dash your foot against a stone.’ ”

7 Jesus said to him, “It is written again, ‘You shall not [a]tempt the Lord your God.’ ”

8 Again, the devil took Him up on an exceedingly high mountain, and showed Him all the kingdoms of the world and their glory. 9 And he said to Him, “All these things I will give You if You will fall down and worship me.”

10 Then Jesus said to him, [b]“Away with you, Satan! For it is written, ‘You shall worship the Lord your God, and Him only you shall serve.’ ”

11 Then the devil left Him, and behold, angels came and ministered to Him.
         </item>

        <item>
             When you face physical danger Acts 27:13-26 13 When the south wind blew softly, supposing that they had obtained their desire, putting out to sea, they sailed close by Crete. 14 But not long after, a tempestuous head wind arose, called [a]Euroclydon. 15 So when the ship was caught, and could not head into the wind, we let her [b]drive. 16 And running under the shelter of an island called [c]Clauda, we secured the skiff with difficulty. 17 When they had taken it on board, they used cables to undergird the ship; and fearing lest they should run aground on the [d]Syrtis Sands, they struck sail and so were driven. 18 And because we were exceedingly tempest-tossed, the next day they lightened the ship. 19 On the third day we threw the ship’s tackle overboard with our own hands. 20 Now when neither sun nor stars appeared for many days, and no small tempest beat on us, all hope that we would be saved was finally given up.

21 But after long abstinence from food, then Paul stood in the midst of them and said, “Men, you should have listened to me, and not have sailed from Crete and incurred this disaster and loss. 22 And now I urge you to take [e]heart, for there will be no loss of life among you, but only of the ship. 23 For there stood by me this night an angel of the God to whom I belong and whom I serve, 24 saying, ‘Do not be afraid, Paul; you must be brought before Caesar; and indeed God has granted you all those who sail with you.’ 25 Therefore take heart, men, for I believe God that it will be just as it was told me. 26 However, we must run aground on a certain island.”
         </item>
        <item>
             When you are discouraged 2nd Corinthians 1:3-11 Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, 4 who comforts us in all our tribulation, that we may be able to comfort those who are in any [a]trouble, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. 5 For as the sufferings of Christ abound in us, so our [b]consolation also abounds through Christ. 6 Now if we are afflicted, it is for your consolation and salvation, which is effective for enduring the same sufferings which we also suffer. Or if we are comforted, it is for your consolation and salvation. 7 And our hope for you is steadfast, because we know that as you are partakers of the sufferings, so also you will partake of the consolation.
Delivered from Suffering

8 For we do not want you to be ignorant, brethren, of our [c]trouble which came to us in Asia: that we were burdened beyond measure, above strength, so that we despaired even of life. 9 Yes, we had the sentence of death in ourselves, that we should not trust in ourselves but in God who raises the dead, 10 who delivered us from so great a death, and [d]does deliver us; in whom we trust that He will still deliver us, 11 you also helping together in prayer for us, that thanks may be given by many persons on [e]our behalf for the gift granted to us through many.
         </item>
        <item>
             when you are bored Psalms 103 Bless the Lord, O my soul;
And all that is within me, bless His holy name!
2
Bless the Lord, O my soul,
And forget not all His benefits:
3
Who forgives all your iniquities,
Who heals all your diseases,
4
Who redeems your life from destruction,
Who crowns you with lovingkindness and tender mercies,
5
Who satisfies your mouth with good things,
So that your youth is renewed like the eagle’s.

6
The Lord executes righteousness
And justice for all who are oppressed.
7
He made known His ways to Moses,
His acts to the children of Israel.
8
The Lord is merciful and gracious,
Slow to anger, and abounding in mercy.
9
He will not always strive with us,
Nor will He keep His anger forever.
10
He has not dealt with us according to our sins,
Nor punished us according to our iniquities.

11
For as the heavens are high above the earth,
So great is His mercy toward those who fear Him;
12
As far as the east is from the west,
So far has He removed our transgressions from us.
13
As a father pities his children,
So the Lord pities those who fear Him.
14
For He [a]knows our frame;
He remembers that we are dust.

15
As for man, his days are like grass;
As a flower of the field, so he flourishes.
16
For the wind passes over it, and it is [b]gone,
And its place remembers it no more.
17
But the mercy of the Lord is from everlasting to everlasting
On those who fear Him,
And His righteousness to children’s children,
18
To such as keep His covenant,
And to those who remember His commandments to do them.

19
The Lord has established His throne in heaven,
And His kingdom rules over all.

20
Bless the Lord, you His angels,
Who excel in strength, who do His word,
Heeding the voice of His word.
21
Bless the Lord, all you His hosts,
You [c]ministers of His, who do His pleasure.
22
Bless the Lord, all His works,
In all places of His dominion.

Bless the Lord, O my soul!
         </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>